CLEA LIN



SUMMARY

Highly motivated postgraduate student in Robotics at UNSW Sydney with 3 years of experience in firmware, software, and robotics research. Expertise in machine learning and computer vision, with a track record of successful research and application. Possess excellent communication skills, an agile mindset, strong problem-solving abilities, and a well-organized approach to tackling challenges.



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Associate

Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica Taipei, Taiwan | Feb. 2022–June 2022

- Topic: Al-Automated Training System for Figure Skating
- Developed an Al-automated training system for figure skating that performed pose tracking on learners' practice videos.
- Trained a frame embedding space model that aligned two similar video sequences temporally.

Research Associate

Center for Artificial Intelligence and Advanced Robotics Taipei, Taiwan | May 2021–Feb. 2022

- Topic: AI Companion Healthcare Aid Robot
- Developed a behaviour recognition warning system for the elderly using human skeleton data and object detection to train a random forest classifier.
- Upgraded a chatting function using NLP techniques and AI-based image understanding to proactively drive the reminiscence process with elderly users.
- Collaborated with professors and external stakeholders to collect and monitor vital signs on the robot system via wearable devices.

Firmware Engineer

Pegatron Corporation

Taipei, Taiwan | Aug. 2019–Jul. 2020

- Improved runtime performance by installing, configuring, and maintaining UEFI.
- Developed and maintained testing scripts that reduced testing time by 70%.
- Provided technical support and troubleshooting to internal stakeholders and external suppliers.



CONTACT

Phone

(+61) 421180529

Email

clealin.rs@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/rong-syuan-lin/

Website

clealin.github.io/



EDUCATION

University of New South Wales,
Sydney, NSW | Expected in Aug 2024

Master of Engineering Science, Robotics

National Tsing Hua University, Hsinchu, Taiwan | June 2019 Bachelor of Science,

Power Mechanical Engineering (Accredited under the Washington Accord)



RELEVANT SKILLS

Programming

C, C++, C#, Python, Java, Pytorch, OpenCV, PowerShell, Batch script, Git

Software and Tools

Jupyter Notebook, TensorFlow, Visual Studio, Android Studio



REFERENCES

Available upon request